<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Sharvil&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://sharvil-turbadkar.github.io/Sharvil.Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Sharvil&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sharvil-turbadkar.github.io/Sharvil.Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Astro-Analytica</title>
      <link>https://sharvil-turbadkar.github.io/Sharvil.Portfolio/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sharvil-turbadkar.github.io/Sharvil.Portfolio/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Astro-Analytica Forecasting outcomes and election polls using twitter sentimental analysis Our main goal is to forecast outcomes of the 2020 election using twitter premium functionality by downloading data per hour from twitter handles
Project Link We have collected our data using twitter premium functionalities
API calls are made using tweepy and the data which has been collected through this API is stored in an S3 bucket.
We then use IAM roles for de-coupling the front end of the application(made using flask) from the back end(data being fetched from S3 bucket)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Sales for FudgeCorporation </title>
      <link>https://sharvil-turbadkar.github.io/Sharvil.Portfolio/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sharvil-turbadkar.github.io/Sharvil.Portfolio/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Analyzing Sale trends for FudgeCorporation Project Link Business Goals: Track Yearly Sales for Fudge Corporation.
1)Create an Integrated, Subject-Oriented, Non-Volatile, Time-Variant Data Warehouse by integrating Fudgeflix and Fudgemart.
2)Analyze the Sales of Fudge Corporation using a Business Intelligence Tool
3)Make Business Recommendations to higher authorities for boosting Sales in the coming fiscal year.
  Tools and Technologies T-SQL, SSIS, SSRS, SSAS, SQL Server, Power BI, Git, GitHub
Process : 1)Data profiling to understand the business requirements of the stakeholders</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie-Feedback-Analysis</title>
      <link>https://sharvil-turbadkar.github.io/Sharvil.Portfolio/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sharvil-turbadkar.github.io/Sharvil.Portfolio/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Heroku App Link Project Link Project Poster   Domain: Movie Industry Client: Rotten Tomato Abstract I synergized alongside my teammates to develop a personalized movie recommender system using Item Based Collaborative Filtering model and proposed an explanation as to why a user has been recommended a particular movie.
Business Goals:  Which attributes will affect the likelihood of watching a movie the most? Do critic and audience views match? Which writers, directors, and studios have the strongest polarity?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter V: Quasimodo</title>
      <link>https://sharvil-turbadkar.github.io/Sharvil.Portfolio/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sharvil-turbadkar.github.io/Sharvil.Portfolio/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>In the twinkling of an eye, all was ready to execute Coppenole’s idea. Bourgeois, scholars and law clerks all set to work. The little chapel situated opposite the marble table was selected for the scene of the grinning match. A pane broken in the pretty rose window above the door, left free a circle of stone through which it was agreed that the competitors should thrust their heads. In order to reach it, it was only necessary to mount upon a couple of hogsheads, which had been produced from I know not where, and perched one upon the other, after a fashion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter IV: Master Jacques Coppenole</title>
      <link>https://sharvil-turbadkar.github.io/Sharvil.Portfolio/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sharvil-turbadkar.github.io/Sharvil.Portfolio/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>While the pensioner of Ghent and his eminence were exchanging very low bows and a few words in voices still lower, a man of lofty stature, with a large face and broad shoulders, presented himself, in order to enter abreast with Guillaume Rym; one would have pronounced him a bull-dog by the side of a fox. His felt doublet and leather jerkin made a spot on the velvet and silk which surrounded him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astro-Analytica</title>
      <link>https://sharvil-turbadkar.github.io/Sharvil.Portfolio/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sharvil-turbadkar.github.io/Sharvil.Portfolio/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Drug-Sentimental-Case-Study Analysis   Stakeholders: Drug Manufacturers Goals: 1)Assist drug manufacturers in making informed decisions 2)Performing Root Cause analysis on the drastic drop in drug ratings over the course of 10 years 3)Predicting patient conditions using multi-class classification(Naive Bayes and SVM) 4)Performing Sentimental analysis to extract subjective information in patient reviews and help build a generalized understanding the effectiveness of the drugs
Python Packages: pandas, Numpy, sklearn, seaborn, wordcloud Approach : 1)Perform extensive exploratory data analysis which involves trimming white spaces, removing stop words, using Snowball stemmer, tokenizing, and vectorizing data after scraping drug reviews online</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
